ShinY
深影
本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
《使女的故事》前情提要
Previously on The Handmaid's Tale...
长期招募翻译人员若干人，请加QQ群327417194（验证：翻译）
■
我杀了弗莱德
I killed Fred.
我觉得应该把弗雷德的葬礼
I think we need to make Fred's funeral
举办成一场令世界瞩目的事件
an international event.
她穿的什么颜色
What was that color?
ShinY
深影
- 紫色代表什么 - 我不知道
- What does purple mean? - I don't know.
■
ShinY
深影
她不再是小女孩了
She's not a little girl anymore.
■
翻译： 221B角落里的花生 财神爷 简单 红豆湾
汉娜穿的紫色衣服 是什么意思
The purple color Hannah was wearing, what does it mean?
新学校 培养主教妻子的学校
New school. Training for future wives.
■
校对：  南瓜大福    压制： AlliumFistulosum
我想留在这里
I want to stay here.
女性在这不安全 尤其是未婚女性
It's not safe for women in this place. Especially unmarried women.
你是个不同寻常的女人 赛丽娜
You're an unusual woman, Serena.
我们这里没有
We don't have the infrastructure
ShinY
深影
■
不同寻常女性的位置
for unusual women.
你将成为全球形象大使
You'll be acting as a global ambassador,
能更好地代表我们神圣的共和国
to best represent our sacred republic.
唯一能够阻止他们的方式
The only way to stop her,
就是送他们去见阎王
and to stop them is to put them all in the fucking ground.
ShinY
深影
她会把这里也变成基列国
She's gonna bring it here.
我发誓 她会把这里变成基列国
I swear to fucking God. She is gonna bring it here.
ShinY
深影
面对一群叛徒者 罪犯和恐怖分子
A bunch of traitors, criminals, terrorists,
你却想欢迎他们回来
and you want to welcome them back.
如果我们继续筑起高墙 闭关锁国
If we keep the walls up and the borders closed,
国家会走向灭亡
this country will die.
欢迎您的光临 我是艾拉妮丝 瑞恩·惠勒的夫人
Welcome to our home. I'm Alanis. Mrs. Ryan Wheeler.
宜应称颂
Praise be.
美国佬滚回家
加拿大厌恶我国难民
Canada's sick of our refugees.
这就是我带你们来到新伯利恒的原因
That's why I brought you to New Bethlehem,
基列国难民愿意重回的家园
where Gilead refugees can come home.
我已经能想象到你和萝丝在这里
I could see you and Rose here.
推你们的孩子荡秋千的画面了
Pushing Junior in a swing.
是吗
Could you now?
我们想知道的有关汉娜的一切
Everything we want to know about Hannah
就在那边
is just there.
我要过去
I'm going across.
今天琼·奥斯本
June Osborn was apprehended today
被我在无人区的一个小分队抓到了
by one of my teams in No Man's Land.
- 琼 - 不要
- June! - No!
我为我们的孩子祈祷 愿她们做得比我们好
I pray for our children. May they do better than we did.
你该不是要生了吧 你现在得去医院
Are you in fucking labor? You're gonna have to go to a hospital.
不行 他们会找到我的
No hospital. They're gonna find me there.
他很健全
He's perfect.
是个完美的男孩
我们找到汉娜了
We found Hannah.
汉娜现在是一个象征了 你也是
Hannah's a symbol now. So are you.
你仍然可以来新伯利恒
You can still come to New Bethlehem.
琼·奥斯本还在惹是生非
June Osborn is still stirring up trouble.
是时候解决这个问题了
It's about time we fixed that problem.
滚出去 政府已土崩瓦解 停止入侵
她不该是我们的目标 大主教
She's not a target, Commander.
枪响之后没有赢家 她也不例外
This is what happens in a fight. Everyone gets bloody.
住手 快住手 你在干什么
Stop! Stop! What the fuck are you doing?
基列想让她生不如死
Gilead wants her to suffer.
他们不会停手 我要你保证会护她周全
They won't stop. So I need to know that you'll protect her.
我很期待与您共事
I look forward to working together.
- 布莱恩 - 你差点杀了她
- Blaine! - You could've fuckin' killed her!
你永远都放不下她 是不是
You will never let go of her, will you?
我努力了 但我做不到
I tried, but I can't.
你以为你是谁
Who do you think you are?
我是弗雷德里克·沃特弗德的夫人
Mrs. Fredrick Waterford.
对我来说你只是一个荡妇
To me, you are just a whore.
请停车 拜托了
Please, stop! Stop, stop!
那个卡车司机 他死了
The man from the truck, died.
他们随时都可能拿到卢克的逮捕令
They could get a signed warrant for Luke at any minute.
我们得离开了
We have to run.
这个国家正在改变
This country is changing.
美国难民正在赶来的路上
American refugees are on their way here.
我们会让他们坐上去西边的火车
We're putting them on trains to go west.
- 我能让你们搭上一班 - 你先走
- I can get you on one. - Go ahead.
- 什么 不行 - 如果他们认出我来
- What? No! - If they recognize me,
你和妮可就都上不去火车了 走吧
they're gonna stop you and Nichole. So just go.
琼 我们会找到彼此 一如既往
June, we're gonna find each other. We always do.
你本来就没想上车 对吧
You were never gonna get on the train, were you?
班科莱先生 你被捕了
Mr. Bankole, you are under arrest.
没事 宝贝 没事的
It's okay, sweetie. It's okay.
我们会找到空位的
We're gonna find some place. Okay?
嗨 琼
Hi, June.
嗨 赛丽娜
Hi, Serena.
使女的故事 第六季第一集
你把鞋子捡起来啦
Hey. You've got your shoes?
你把鞋捡起来了 好宝贝 真棒
You've got your shoes there. Good girl. Good girl.
妈妈来了 妈妈来了
Here comes Mommy. Here comes Mommy.
妈妈总会回来
Mommies always come back. Yeah.
是的 妈妈回来了
Yes. Here she is.
- 哦 去吧 - 来吧 小宝贝
- Oh, there we go. - Come here, my love.
好了
Okay.
要不要坐到这边 亲爱的 来吧
Should we go sit over here, honey? Come on.
你想坐到那里吗
You wanna sit up there?
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 那就坐这里吧 - 你饿了吗
- Well, okay. - Hi, are you hungry?
抱歉 洗手间里排着长队呢
I'm sorry, there was along line at the rest room.
没关系 真的
It's a pleasure. Seriously.
我感觉这几天
I, um... I haven't been able to put him down...
他都没离开过我的手
in days, it feels like.
没人能帮我搭把手
There just hasn't been anybody else to hold him.
但现在我们安全了 可以休息了
But now we're safe, we can rest.
我得睡一会儿 我快累死了
Yeah. Well, I'm gonna get some sleep 'cause I'm fucking exhausted,
我的胳膊也痛得要命
and my arm is fucking killing me.
当然了 抱歉
Right, of course. Sorry.
你的手臂骨折了 肯定很痛
Um, your arm is broken. It must be quite painful.
你怎么弄的
How did you break it?
车祸
a car accident.
就在我家门口 一辆车从我身上轧了过去
A car ran over me in front of my house.
不是吧 什么时候
Pardon? When?
昨天
Yesterday.
我没听错吧 昨天一辆车从你身上轧过去了
I'm sorry, a car ran over you yesterday?
是的 昨天早上
Yeah. Yesterday morning.
是辆卡车 不是轿车
It was a truck. It was not a car.
过马路勤看路
Always look both ways.
好吧 你真是个相当顽强的女人
Well, you are, uh... one exceptionally tough woman.
谢谢你
Thank you.
是基列国干的
It was Gilead.
他们想要我的命
They tried to kill me.
这么说他们看我俩都不顺眼
It seems they are unhappy with both of us.
我们不一样 但是...
Well, we're not the same, but...
敌人的敌人就是朋友
The enemy of my enemy is my friend.
视情况而定
On a case-by-case basis.
现在你可以把一切抛之脑后了
Well, now you can put all of that behind you.
借你吉言 赛丽娜
From your mouth to God's ears, Serena.
自逃亡以来
Well, he's been smiling on us so far, since...
祂一直对我们眷顾有加
since we've been on the run.
你干嘛说得这么浪漫
Why do you make it sound romantic?
我不是故意的 一直提心吊胆
That is unintentional. I don't think there's anything romantic
并无浪漫可言
about being absolutely terrified all of the time.
到了今晚
And by tonight,
多伦多和惠勒夫妇将会在千里之外
Toronto and the Wheelers will be 1,000 miles away.
基列国也是
And Gilead will be 1,000 miles away, too.
明天我们就能告别过去
Tomorrow, we can start to forget.
亲爱的 妮可
Sweetie. Nichole?
该死 完蛋了
Shit, shit, shit, shit.
亲爱的 妮可 不好意思 借过一下
Sweetie, Nichole? Excuse me. Excuse me.
妮可 你在哪里
Nichole... honey?
妮可 宝贝 不好意思
Nichole, sweetie? Excuse me.
- 没关系 - 该死 真见鬼
- Yeah, no problem. - Shit, shit, shit, shit.
妮可 宝贝
Nichole? Honey?
嗨
Hi!
不好意思
Excuse me.
嗨 宝贝
Hi, sweetheart. Hi!
你醒了吗
Did you wake up?
是啊 你睡得正香
Ah, she did. You were still sleeping.
来吧 小宝贝
Come here, sweetie-pie.
找到你了
I've got you.
来妈妈这里 很好
Come here, come here. There we go.
好了 宝贝
There we go. Okay, sweetie.
别再这样了
Don't you ever do that again.
我担心你没有休息好的话
I was concerned that you might be ill-tempered
会影响情绪
if you didn't get enough rest.
我真傻
Silly me.
别碰我的孩子
Just keep your fucking hands off my kid!
听懂了吗
Do you understand me?
好的 我明白了
Okay. Yes, I understand you.
你觉得我会偷走你的女儿吗
What, you think I'm going to steal your daughter?
趁你睡着 像迪士尼反派那样
While you're sleeping, like some kind of Disney villain?
我真服了 琼 清醒一点
For God's sake, June, that's completely idiotic.
你还好吗 你脸好红
Are you all right? You look flushed.
我没事 这里太热了
I'm fine. I'm fine. It's just... it's hot in here.
别碰我
Don't touch me!
行行行 我从你包里拿了块米糕给她
Okay. All right, well, I gave her a rice cake out of your diaper bag,
希望你别介意
I hope that's okay.
当然了 根据你的剧本应该是颗毒苹果
I'm sure that you expected a poisoned apple.
不过她还是很饿
She's still hungry, though.
还有其他吃的吗
Is there any other food?
橱柜已经空了 但他们发了这些
I'm afraid the cupboard is bare, but they did pass these out.
宜应称颂
Praise be.
别在这里说祷言 会有人听到
Don't say that in here. Someone may hear you.
好了
Okay.
这些人是哪儿来的
Where did all these people come from?
大约六小时前 我们经过温尼伯
We passed through Winnipeg about six hours ago,
他们又挂了几节车厢 难民人数激增
and they added a lot more cars, a lot more people.
没有信号
There's no fucking service.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
不好 我们走吧
No. Okay, let's go, uh...
来吧 亲爱的 我们得找点吃的
Come on, sweetie. We're gonna go get some more food.
走吧 亲爱的
All right, honey. Okay.
我们又该去哪里呢 琼
And where is there to go, June?
你知道我们在行驶的列车上 对吧
I mean, you realize we're on a moving train, right?
这里肯定有非政府组织
There has to be an NGO... somewhere.
他们会有食物 说不定还有卫星电话
And they're gonna have food, and maybe a satellite phone
我要给我丈夫打个电话
'cause I need to talk to my husband.
- 好 - 不 不 你待在这里
- Okay. - No, no, you stay here.
你知道我们一起行动才更有胜算
You have to agree it makes sense for us to stick together.
赛丽娜 我们不是一伙的 明白吗
Serena, we are not together, okay?
请问这里有非政府组织车厢之类的地方吗
Excuse me, do you know if there's an NGO car or anything like that?
我不知道 他们说如果要领食物就去那边
Oh, I don't know. They said there was food that way if we wanted.
- 六号车厢 - 谢谢
- Car six, whatever that means. - Thank you.
但你未必能过去
I don't think you can make it through, though.
好了 亲爱的 我们要去找点吃的 好吗
Okay, sweetie, we're just gonna get some food, okay?
你会没事的
You're all right. You're okay.
好了
Okay.
慢点 你还好吗
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Are you okay?
- 别碰我 - 你不舒服
- Don't touch me, okay? - You're sick.
- 别碰... 把手拿开 - 好
- Get... just... hands off me! - Okay.
好吧 你待在这里
All right. Why don't you stay right here?
她还好吗
Is she okay?
我会给你换条干净的
...get you a clean one.
- 我保证 - 打扰了
- I promise. - Excuse me.
- 还好吗 - 这边
- All right? - Right here.
我给你找了个医生
I got you a doctor.
什么
What?
你好 怎么了
Hello. What's going on?
真是够了
Jesus Christ.
我没... 你有电话吗
I, um... Look, do you have a working phone?
我们来做个交易 只要你接受治疗
Let's make a deal. You let me treat you,
我就让你打电话
and then you can call whomever you want.
- 好吧 - 手臂怎么了
- Fine. - What happened here?
骨折了
I broke it.
看起来你近期
Ah, it looks like you had...
做过修复手术对吗
...some recent surgical repair?
她有的
Yes, she did.
或许你朋友能照看一下你的女儿
Maybe your friend could take your daughter for a moment.
- 好啊 - 不了
- Yes! - No.
你的缝线可能断开了
Uh, you've probably torn a few sutures.
我需要看看底下怎么样 很快的
I need to have a look under there. I'll be quick.
当然可以 我很乐意照看她
Of course, I'm happy to.
行吧
Fine. Fine.
宝贝 妈妈就在旁边 好吗
Okay, sweetie. Mommy's right here, okay?
- 对 - 好的
- Yeah. - Okay.
来吧 你好呀
Come here. Hi.
你能不能给她找块干净的尿布
Maybe you could find her a clean diaper or something?
当然可以 别紧张 琼 我不会离开
Yes, relax, June. I'm not going anywhere.
你的伤口感染得很严重
Looks like you have a nice infection boiling in here.
这就是为什么母亲和孩子应当受到照顾
Yeah, see, this is why mothers and children should be cared for.
我们是列车上最重要的人
We are the most important people on the train.
你等下也应该请布兰特医生看看
You should see Dr. Brandt next.
好 谢谢你
Oh, okay. Thank you.
好的
All right.
你好呀
Hey.
先生 沃顿大主教已经在等你了
Sir, High Commander Wharton's been waiting for you.
祈神保佑
Blessed day.
早上好 先生
Morning, sir.
真是个惊喜啊
It's a nice surprise.
我想应该好好庆祝你重获自由
Well, I thought we should celebrate your freedom.
她...
She's, uh...
生我气是应该的
right to be upset with me.
萝丝生性敏感
Well, Rosie's always been sensitive.
但你们还有一辈子去寻找解决之道
But you two have a lifetime together to figure that out.
夫妻之间的事只有他们和上帝知道
What happens between a man and wife is between them and God.
我知道我需要
I know I need to, uh...
和劳伦斯大主教谈谈
talk to Commander Lawrence.
是的
Yes, you do.
我当时脑子一片空白
I wasn't thinking straight.
思绪混乱
Lost my head.
我会帮你好好解释的
I'll try and smooth it over with him.
其实我不怪你
Look, I can't say I blame you.
我们当中谁没受过诱惑
Who amongst us hasn't been tempted?
但你不觉得是时候放下那些幼稚的念头了吗
But don't you think maybe it's time to put away those childish things?
不论它们再怎么引人入胜 迷惑心智
No matter how fun and diverting they may be?
也该分清主次吧
Prioritize?
是不是该以家事为先
Prioritize what's best for you and your family?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
抱歉 我听起来好像块幸运饼干
I'm sorry, I sound like a fortune cookie.
我想说的是 尼克
All of that is to say, Nick,
你拥有光明的未来
you have a bright future.
如果你能把握住
It's yours,
那么你将前途无量
if you take it.
谢谢你 先生
Thank you, sir.
我就知道你会明白
I knew you'd understand.
我要去俱乐部 看看能不能
I'm gonna go to the club, see if I can catch Lawrence
在劳伦斯打完前找到他 给你求求情
on the back nine. Plead your case a little.
我们今晚家里见
But I'll see you at home tonight.
您不回特区了吗
You're, uh, not going back to D.C.?
不了 我不在华盛顿
No, I think they can get by without me...
一时半刻也出不了问题
for a while.
我想多陪陪萝丝
I want to spend some time close to Rose.
我要有孙子了
I have a grandson on the way.
以家事为先 记得吗
Priorities, remember?
靠
Fuck.
你能把行李箱挪开吗
Could you move those suitcases out of the way there?
借过一下
Excuse me, guys.
不好意思
Excuse me.
你能腾出点地方吗 我们需要点空间
Can you make a little room? We could use some space.
感谢施惠 希望你可以理解
Beg your grace. I hope you can understand,
- 我们只是需要点空间 谢谢 - 好的
- we just need a space of our own. Thanks. - Yeah.
我过去拿包 来吧 朋友们
Yeah, I'll grab my bag there. C'mon, guys.
请坐这里 过来吧 好多了
Here, please. Come in. Much better.
瞧 我们现在有一块妇幼专区了
See, now we have a space for women and children.
你给卢克打电话了吗
Did you call Luke?
没有 我跟莫伊拉通过话了
No. I talked to my friend, Moira.
有什么消息吗 你丈夫怎么样了
Well, any news? What's going on with your husband?
他被逮捕了 好吗
He's been arrested, okay?
来吧 亲爱的 我们走
Come on, honey. Let's go.
亲爱的 你怎么样
Hi, sweetie. How you doing?
喝点果汁好不好
Let's get some juice, huh?
真棒
There we go.
卢克在监狱里
Luke is in jail.
他为了保护我才遭到逮捕
He was arrested for defending me.
撞我的人死了
The man who ran me over died.
上帝的正义终将实现
God's justice will prevail.
卢克会在温哥华与你重聚
Luke will find you in Vancouver.
基列国将成为过去 你的家人会再度团圆
Gilead won't matter, and your family will be together again.
赛丽娜
Serena.
汉娜
Hannah.
汉娜 她还被困在那里 记得吗
Hannah. She's still there. Remember?
她被绑架了 依然是基列国的囚犯
She was kidnapped, and she's still a prisoner.
你说得对
You're right.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我说错话了
I misspoke.
请原谅
Please forgive me.
好吧
Okay.
莫伊拉说我们不是去温哥华
Moira said that we're not going to Vancouver.
温哥华现在人满为患 他们不让火车进站了
They're overwhelmed, and they won't let the train come in.
好吧
All right.
那我们要去哪儿
Then where are we going?
她还不知道
She doesn't know yet.
我... 我也不知道
So I... I don't know.
但我知道我的丈夫不会在那里
But I know my husband won't be there.
祂会为你找到一条路 让你和家人重聚
By His hand, you will find a way to bring your family back together,
琼 那是你的天赋
June, that is your gift.
只要有一线希望 你总能找到出路
If it is at all possible, you will find a way.
我不知道自己是否还能独自面对一切
I don't know if I can be alone again.
那我们就一起找出路 我会帮你
Then we will find a way. I will help you.
我不需要你的帮助
I don't want your help.
我知道你不想接受我的帮助
I know you don't want my help. I realize that.
你不必非得接受我的帮助 我也理解 但是
And you don't have to accept it, and I understand that, too. But...
上帝希望我帮你
God would want me to help.
我必须这么做
I need to...
在经历了这一切之后
after everything.
好吧
Okay.
情况不容乐观
That's not good.
和奥乔亚上校确认后立即送出
Confirm with Colonel Ochoa, and send it first thing.
务必做到优先处理
Make it happen.
这就去办
Will do.
我不想等着预约
I'm not going to wait for an appointment.
整条街的电子眼 我一个不漏全调出来了
I got footage from every doorbell camera on the street.
卢克当时是在保护琼 他动手是出于自卫
Luke was protecting June, he fought the guy off in self-defense.
好吧
Okay.
知道了 我会负责协商 尽我所能
Um, I'll make the calls, do what I can.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
我也是这么回答那些难民的
How I say that to 100 refugees every day
可我明知自己无能为力
when I know I can't do a thing.
如今在加拿大做美国人实在不易
It's not a good time to be an American in Canada.
还真是头一次听说呢
No? That's news.
不是
No...
他们 呃
they're, uh...
准备关掉这里
getting ready to shut this place down.
整个部门一年内就会消失
This entire office could be gone in a year.
什么 他们怎么能这样做
What? How can they do that?
内阁希望与基列国关系正常化
The Cabinet wants to start normalizing relations with Gilead.
这意味着他们不再承认美国政府的合法地位
That would mean de-recognizing the United States.
我们不能就这么认输了
We can't just let them win.
我们军力透支
Our military's depleted...
已经无力抗衡
no match.
所以就这样了
So that's it?
我们不反抗了吗
We're done fighting back?
五月天还在反抗
Mayday's fighting back.
我以为你不会和五月天合作
I thought you didn't work with Mayday.
我们不剩多少朋友了
We don't have many friends left.
能并肩即是盟友
You find your allies where you can.
我想要帮忙
I wanna help.
我必须去帮忙
I need to help.
你肯定需要有人穿越边境 潜入内部
I mean, you must need people to cross the border, get inside.
我以前在荡妇俱乐部见过那些勾当
Shit, all that black market shit I saw when I was at Jezebel's, it's...
基列国的地下俱乐部 供政权高层人物进行非法和堕落的活动
总得找法子进去
it's got to come in somehow.
什么 你... 你在那个俱乐部待过
What... you were... you were at Jezebel's?
没人能离开那个地方
No one leaves Jezebel's.
你怎么出来的
How'd you get out?
我宰了个大主教
I killed a Commander.
肃然起敬
That's something.
他们把我送去马大培训学校
They sent me to Martha school.
可惜失败了
Yeah, it didn't take.
他们把我当球踢来踢去
They kicked me around, and then
把我送到农业垦殖区
sent me to an agricultural colony.
至少我还有口饭吃
So I ate, at least.
上个月才被人从边境解救出来
Was liberated at the border last month.
上帝的恩典与你同在
God's grace was on you.
救我的可不是上帝
It wasn't God,
我们有个机智过人 心怀热忱的医生
we had a really smart doctor who gave a shit.
我相信这也是上帝的恩典
Well, I'm sure that was God's grace as well.
女士 我在荡妇俱乐部待了十七个月
I was in a Jezebel's for 17 months, ma'am.
上帝只是男人使用两样东西的借口
God is just an excuse for men to use two things,
屌和枪
cocks and guns.
自钱德拉两岁后我就再也没见过她
I haven't seen my Chandra since she was two.
我逃出来了 可我的小宝贝还在那里
I'm out, but my baby girl is still there.
感觉就像被人生生从身上挖走一块肉
It feels like a piece of your body is gone.
她们还活着 如果真死了 反倒痛快
They aren't gone. If they were gone, it would be easier.
不
No.
不是这样的
No. That's not true.
我真的很抱歉
Well, I'm so sorry.
看来我们这里的每个人 或多或少
It seems like all of us here, at some point or another,
都曾经受暴力牵连
were a part of some kind of violence.
是啊 你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
是啊
Yeah.
我的女儿 汉娜 是在森林里被抓的
My daughter, Hannah, was captured in the forest.
卫士将我们逼离公路
The Guardians ran us off the road,
他们穷追不舍
and they chased us down.
汉娜非常害怕
Hannah was so scared.
我也吓坏了
And I was terrified.
太可怕了
That's awful.
当时我们离边境只有半英里
We were only half a mile from the border.
但我无法跑得更快
I just couldn't... I couldn't run fast enough.
别这么说
Don't say that.
他们可是武装士兵
They were soldiers.
我是她妈妈
I'm her mom.
他们抓住我的时候 我还抱着她
And when they, uh, caught me, I was holding her,
他们硬生生把她夺走了
and they pulled her away.
他们拽着她 我...
They were pulling her, and I...
我松手了
I let go.
我松开了她
I let her go.
愿主治愈伤痛
May God heal you.
听到这些 真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
是啊
Yeah.
我也希望它能减轻我的痛苦
I wish that helped.
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
好多了 谢谢
Much better, thanks.
我能看看吗
Can I take a look?
好 宝贝 来吧
Okay, sweetie. Come on.
你和那位旅伴的交情有多深
How well do you know your traveling companion?
我们认识有些日子了
Um, we've known each other a while.
但愿不是太久
Not too long, I'd hope.
是不太久
No, not too long.
她可不是你以为的那种人
I don't think she is who you think she is.
她是个难民
Well, she's... she's a refugee.
如果你知道她是谁
If you knew who she was,
你绝不会让她靠近你女儿
you wouldn't be letting her anywhere near your daughter.
我怀疑她是持伪造证件的战犯
I think she's a war criminal traveling under false papers.
等抓到她自然会查清楚
They'll make sure when they arrest her.
我已经联系了安全局
I talked to the security people.
他们正派警员前来抓捕
They're sending an officer to come and get her.
什么时候
When?
我想应该快到了
I think they're on their way.
她是咎由自取
It's what she deserves.
这还算是便宜她了
It's better than she deserves.
请答应我一件事
Just promise me one thing, okay?
答应我护她幼子周全
Promise me that we will keep her baby safe.
可以吗
All right?
我们的小家伙怎么样啊
And how are we doing?
挺好的 谢谢关心
I think very well, thank you.
让我来看看这位小绅士
Let me take a look at that young man.
好啦 好啦
There we go. Oh, there we go.
他们很珍贵 对吧
They're so precious, you know?
他看起来是个健康的小男孩
And he seems like a very healthy young boy.
没事的
It's okay.
宜应称颂 对吧
Praise be for that, right?
跟我说说孩子的父亲吧
But tell me about his father.
他死在战场了
Oh, um, he died in the war.
愿他的记忆成为祝福
May his memory be a blessing.
说起来 我在基列国是搞生育科学的
You know, in Gilead, I worked mostly in fertility sciences.
当然 实验室里全是男人
And it was all men, of course, in the lab.
是挺奇怪的
It was odd.
所以你自然会对造访的女性印象深刻
And you certainly remembered when there was a woman around.
我从未忘记
I never forgot.
可以想象 孩子该换尿布了
I imagine. Um, I think he needs a diaper change, actually.
马上哄好了
Almost done here.
大主教们常来参观实验室
And Commanders would visit the lab all the time.
偶尔 非常偶尔
Sometimes, rarely actually,
当他们对本所研究感兴趣时
they would bring their wives...
会带妻子同来
when they were interested.
他们会问出
Sometimes they asked...
相当高明的问题
the most intelligent questions.
请把我的儿子还给我
Please give me my son.
医生 孩子想要妈妈
Doctor, I think he misses his mommy.
他可真是...
He's really...
一个漂亮的男孩啊 沃特弗德夫人
a beautiful boy, Mrs. Waterford.
赛丽娜·乔伊
Serena Joy.
- 不可能吧 - 天呐 真的是她
- No fucking way. - My God, it's her.
该死的赛丽娜·乔伊
Fucking Serena Joy.
你怎么到这儿来的
How did you get on here?
她肯定伪造身份了
I bet she has fake papers.
她之前被关在多伦多
She was detained in Toronto.
- 是她 - 没错 我之前是在多伦多
- That's her. - Yes. I was in Toronto.
我希望我的儿子能够拥有自由 所以我离开了基列
I left Gilead because I wanted freedom for my son.
无人在意
Who cares?
这鬼地方是你亲手建立的
You built the fucking place. It belongs to you.
你休想瞒天过海 逃脱罪责
You're the rat that doesn't get to jump off the ship.
你这个鼠辈 你死定了
You're the rat that sinks!
嘿 别这样 冷静点
Wait, wait. No, no, calm down.
- 我怎么冷静 - 你可...
- Don't tell me to calm down. - Just...
那个该死的女人
That fucking bitch!
- 你能冷静下来的 - 你被洗脑了吗
- You're gonna calm down. - You brainwashed?
相信我
Okay?
- 她没资格站在这里 - 她抢走了我们的孩子
- She doesn't deserve to be here. - She stole our children!
她是罪人
She's a criminal!
- 她以为自己是谁 - 警察要来了
- Who does she think she is? - The police are coming.
她会被逮捕
They're going to arrest her.
我向加拿大边防局举报了她
I reported her to the DCBS...
- 什么 - 他们指派了警员过来
- What? - They're sending an officer.
- 他应该在来的路上了 - 不
- He should be on his way. - No!
不要举报我 别把我交给警方
No, please do not report me! Do not give me over to the police!
这点惩罚对你来说算轻的了
You are getting off easy.
琼 要是我在加拿大被捕
If... June, if I'm arrested in Canada, they will...
他们会把诺亚送回惠勒夫妇那儿
they'll give Noah back to the Wheelers,
我就再也见不到他了
and I'll never see him again.
琼 求你帮帮我
June, please, help me.
你怎么老是看不清状况
How can you be so fucking blind sometimes?
- 还指望别人帮你 - 她看得清
- Fucking help you? - She isn't blind.
- 但她该瞎 - 别这样
- But she should be. - Hey.
- 住手 - 我们应该割了她的舌头
- Stop it. - We can cut out her tongue.
- 好主意 - 说得对
- Great idea. - Yeah.
我们试试看吧 沃特弗德夫人
Let's see it, Mrs. Waterford.
够了
Enough.
他们砍了她的手指
They took her finger, all right?
她站出来了 他们就砍了她的手指
She spoke out, and they took her finger.
她已经付出代价了
She has paid.
- 她已经付出代价了 - 你怎么还在为她说话
- She has paid, okay? - How can you defend her?
她冷血无情 草菅人命
She threw people off fucking rooftops.
她配称为女性吗
Gender traitors?
这些债你怎么偿
How do you pay for that?
在基列国成立之前 美国已经是人间炼狱
Before Gilead, America was full of horrors.
- 别说了 赛丽娜 - 每一天都有女人被强奸 被杀害
- Serena, shut up. - Women were getting raped, and killed every day,
可是没有人在乎 那就是你们的国家
and nobody cared. And that was your country.
- 你在胡说些什么 - 你们根本无法生存
- What is wrong with you? - You were unfit.
- 你们的遭遇与我无关 - 你偷走了我们的孩子
- I am not responsible for your tragedies! - You stole our children!
我没有抢走你们的孩子
Your children were not taken from you!
我没有偷走他们 我是在救他们
They weren't stolen, they were saved!
赛丽娜 别说了
Serena, shut up!
- 她是强奸犯 - 美国背弃了上帝
- She's a rapist! - God hated America
所以上帝厌弃美国
because America turned their back on God.
于是祂将你们的国家抹去 天佑美国
And God took your country away. God blessed America!
- 赛丽娜 够了 - 她该经受业火焚烧
- Serena! - She should burn in hell!
警官
Officer.
你该庆幸 警察至少能保你平安
The police will keep you safe, safer than you deserve.
- 就是她吗 - 是的警官
- That's her? - Yes, officer.
赛丽娜·乔伊·沃特弗德
Serena Joy Waterford.
想必您拿到了逮捕令
I believe there's a warrant for her arrest.
- 你有证件吗 - 都是假的
- Do you have papers? - They're all fake.
她是个罪犯
She's a criminal!
她背叛了女性
She's a traitor to women!
这些看上去没问题
Yeah, okay. These seem legit.
不对
No.
给你添麻烦了
Sorry to bother you.
警官 等一等 听我说
No, no. Sir? Sir? No, officer? Sir? Listen to me.
- 这就是赛丽娜·沃特弗德 - 别说了
- This is Serena Waterford. Okay? - Stop it.
- 别说了 - 相信我 听我的
- Stop it. - Trust me. Trust me.
你闭上嘴
Shut up.
这是赛丽娜·沃特弗德
This is Serena Waterford.
- 在基列国的时候 - 琼
- I know because she was my mistress... - June.
- 我是她的使女 - 我不理解 她侵犯了你
- ...in Gilead. - Jesus fucking Christ. She raped you.
你必须逮捕她
And you have to arrest her. Okay?
求你了 警官
Please, sir.
你必须把她和孩子从这儿带走
You have to take her and the baby out of here.
就是她
All right? This is her.
请你逮捕她
You have to arrest her.
听我的 赛丽娜
Just trust me, Serena.
她在想些什么
What's wrong with her?
女士 你有个漂亮的孩子
You have a beautiful baby, ma'am.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我也曾有妻儿
I had a son. And a wife.
她死在了殖民地
She died in The Colonies.
如果他还活着 也快十一岁了
He'd be almost 11.
你并不是赛丽娜·乔伊
You look nothing like Serena Joy.
打扰了 女士们
Sorry for the interruption, ladies.
- 警官 你不能就这么走了 - 警官
- No, officer. Sir? Officer! - Officer? Uh... uh...
警官
Sir? Sir?
想离开的人 现在可以走了
If anyone wants to leave, they should go.
好吧 这边 慢慢来 没事的
Okay. Okay. Come on. Come through. Come through. It's okay.
往前走
Let's go. Let's go.
离我远一点
Back away from me.
你让人恶心
You're disgusting!
- 琼 - 她们走不掉的
- June? - They'll never get out.
不要伤害我的孩子 别靠近我 琼 救救我
Don't come any closer to my baby! Get away from me! June!
没事的 退后 没事的
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay. Back off. It's okay.
你不会因此获得平静
This is not going to bring you any peace.
- 你不该趟这趟浑水 - 走开
- You should leave. - Get out of the way.
- 不 - 抓住她
- No. - Get her.
不要这样做 不要这样做
Hey, hey, hey. Hey. Don't do this. Don't do this.
她不配有孩子
She doesn't deserve to have a baby.
下地狱去吧
Rot in hell.
求求你们 不要碰我
Please don't. Please don't touch me! Please!
请不要碰我
Please don't touch me.
赛丽娜 把孩子给我
Serena. Give me the baby.
求求你们 停下来
Please, stop.
求你们了 我还有孩子
Please, please! Please, I have a baby.
- 恶毒的女人 - 把孩子给我
- A fucking monster! - Give me the baby.
把诺亚交给我
Give me Noah.
- 琼 帮帮我 - 把孩子给我 赛丽娜
- June! June! - Give me the baby, Serena.
请让我带走孩子吧
I'm just taking the baby. Please let me take the baby.
琼
June!
我们走
Come on. Go.
快来
Come on, come on.
赛丽娜 恐怕你得跳车了
Serena, you have to jump.
把门打开
Open the door!
- 你准备好了吗 - 上帝啊
- Serena? - Oh, my God.
- 我能去哪里呢 - 赛丽娜 你必须跳车
- Where am I gonna go? - Serena, you have to jump.
- 我不能下车 - 赛丽娜 你可以的 该死
- I can't get off the train. - Serena, yes you can. Shit.
- 把玻璃打碎 - 我做不到
- Break the glass! - I can't.
这是你唯一的生路
There's nowhere to go.
她们会伤害诺亚
They're gonna hurt Noah.
赛丽娜 你只能跳车了 明白吗
Listen to me, Serena! You have  to get off the train. Okay?
琼 我做不到
June, I can't do it.
去吧
Go.
她逃走了
Fuck! She's gone.
你这个叛徒
You fucking traitor!
醒醒
Hey, wake up!
终点站阿拉斯加到了
It's Alaska! End of the line.
全部人都要下车 女士
I've got a whole train to clean, lady.
抱歉
Sorry.
- 打扰一下 - 新来的
- Excuse me. - New arrival?
没错
Yeah.
先去做个体检
Start in medical.
好的
Okay.
劳恩
Rohen?
横地
Yokochi?
在这里 我们一家三口
That's us, family of three.
索尔伯格
Solberg?
本森
Benson!
亲爱的 没事的
It's okay, sweetie.
没事
Okay.
宝贝
Okay, honey.
- 下一个 - 快到我们了 宝贝
- Next! - We're almost there, sweetheart.
就快了
We're almost there.
马上就有食物和干净尿布了
We're gonna get you some food, and a diaper.
琼
June!
琼·奥斯本
June Osborn!
亲爱的
Sweetheart?
妈妈
Mom?
■
更多精彩 请登录深影论坛 sybbs.vip
深影字幕组微博 weibo.com/syfansub
■
关注深影字幕组
微信公众号，更
多影视资讯，等
你来发现